

Magdalena Kortas

Data Scientist, Machine
Learning Engineer

Skills & Certifications & Awards

Artificial Intelligence
Machine Learning
SQL
Big Data
Predictive Modelling & Analytics
Data Analysis, Wrangling & Mining
Deep Learning
Natural Language Processing
Visualisation
AWS
HTML/CSS
Statistics

Python

Keras, Pandas, Flask, NumPy, Matplotlib, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Plotly, Seaborn, Pyspark, Dash

R

Tidyverse, GGplot2, Shiny, Lubridate, DT, Plotly, e1071, StringR, Data.table, Caret

Certifications

Certified Analytics Professional CAP® (Institute for Operations Research and the Management Sciences, 2022)

Awards

Women in AI Hero (AI4EU Consortium, 2021) O'Reilly Scholar (USA, 2020)

Languages

Polish Native English C1 Spanish B2/C1

Phone:

(+48) 533 490 194

Github:

@m-kortas

E-mail:

magdalenekortas@gmail.com

Linkedin:

@mkortas

I am an ambitious, internationally recognised and certified Data Science expert with 4 years of professional experience in Data Science & Machine Learning gained in both the private and civic sector, working on international projects connected to 7 out of 10 Australia's key target sectors. Currently developing an Artificial Intelligence solution to fight water pollution and floods in Northern America.

I am passionate about and specialised in building AI for Good solutions and my current objective is to <u>bring innovation to Australia and target with AI the most important challenge of the 21st century</u> - climate change counteraction (We need to take bold action now!).

Work Experience



Carl Data Solutions 10.2021 - present Data Scientist (Infrastructure)

- Developing AI to fight water pollution and floods by predicting sewer overflow events for smart cities' waste disposal infrastructure in Northern America
- Developing AI for automatically cleaning and performing quality control on time-series data derived from sensors

Python, Github, Kafka, Kubernetes



Magdalena Kortas Data Solutions 07.2019 - present Owner/Senior Data Scientist

Providing Data Science, AI and Research and Development (R&D) solutions for Polish and British companies, writing technical and non-technical articles about Data Science and AI, specialised translations to English, Spanish and Polish (Data Science/AI specialist terminology)



Ihs Markit (S&P Global) 03.2021 - 09.2021* Senior Data Scientist (Transport)

Supporting analytics application in the field of waterborne flows of commodities around the World to deliver actionable insights and support informed trading decisions

Python, GitLab, AWS
// * left due to a career growth opportunity

"Once I wanted to travel to discover the world. But I realised that everything has already been discovered. Then I decided to become a Data Scientist to discover what was left to discover" Magdalena Kortas

Memberships & Publications

Memberships

- International Society for Data Science and Analytics (ISDSA)
- WomenTech Network
- Women in AI

Publications

- Published essay in "Analytics Interpreted" USA, 2021
- "Creating an AI to combat environmental pollution" Towards Data Science, 2021
- <u>"Sound-based bird</u> <u>classification"</u> Towards Data Science, 2020

Education

Infoshare Academy 01.2018 - 07.2018

Diploma, Data Science

An intensive on-site training: SQL, R, Python, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, data visualisation, wrangling and analysis

Gdansk University of Technology 10.2015 - 10.2017

MSc, Economic Analytics (in English)

R, VBA, SQL, data mining, data forecasting, quantitative and qualitative data analysis, network analysis

Hobbies

AI for Good Travelling (49 countries visited) Healthy Lifestyle Personal Development

Work Experience



Nordea Bank 04.2018 - 07.2019*

Junior Data Scientist (Finance)

Reducing fraud and financial crime in Norway, Sweden, Denmark and Finland by applying and building analytical capabilities

R, Python, SQL, Bitbucket, PowerBI // * team closed in Poland

Volunteering



Women in Machine Learning & Data Science Trojmiasto 07.2018 - present

Co-founder/Lead ML Engineer

Supporting and promoting practising and studying machine learning and data science in the region.

Projects:

- <u>AI to Combat Environmental Pollution</u> detecting plastic waste in the environment to combat environmental pollution and promote circular economy
- <u>Sound-based Bird Classification</u> using AI, acoustics and ornithology to classify birds in the environment, an environmental awareness project



Omdena 01.2020 - 01.2021 Lead ML Engineer (Education/Health)

Building innovative, ethical, and efficient AI and Data Science solutions to real-world problems.

Projects:

- <u>Analyzing the Importance of Sex Education in Poland with AI</u> by Exploring Sexually-related Topics Using Natural Language Processing
- <u>COVID-19 Global AI Challenge</u>: Applying AI to help vulnerable populations



Eindhoven University of Technology 09.2020 - 10.2020 Data Scientist (Energy)

Participation in the 10th Data Challenge week.

Project:

- Adoption of renewable energy sources to reduce Co2 emissions' growth in the Netherlands

"Once I wanted to travel to discover the world. But I realised that everything has already been discovered. Then I decided to become a Data Scientist to discover what was left to discover" Magdalena Kortas